<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Story World</string>
        <string name="story1" >
        Adam lived in a small village in the south of Poland near to the big city of Krakow. Adam’s favourite part of the day was dinner time. Not because his mother made the best food in the whole world, but because, at dinner time, the whole family would sit around the television and watch the news. No school lesson could compare to the stories Adam watched on the news: exotic looking people from different cultures, natural disasters in countries he had never visited and insights into the coolest celebrities and their extraordinary lives. It was one such story that changed Adam’s life forever ...
        One evening, just before harvest, the family was sitting round enjoying steaming bowls of chicken soup with homemade macaroni when the news began. The top story was about a mysterious robbery from Wawel Castle in the nearby city of Krakow. During the night, thieves had snuck in and taken the treasure from Smok’s lair!
        Everybody in Poland knows the story of Smok the Dragon who lived in Wawel Castle many hundreds of years ago. Smok lived in the caves beneath the castle and used to eat the King’s cattle. The King offered his daughter’s hand in marriage to the man who could slay the mighty dragon. Many brave knights and noblemen tried and failed, but in the end it was a simple cobbler who had slain the mighty dragon.
        As every school girl and boy knows, dragons sleep on a bed of gold treasure. Smok’s lair had such a bed of gold, and when the dragon was slain, the King did not move the gold because he wanted other dragons to think that Smok still lived in Wawel Castle. ‘That way,’ the King had exclaimed, ‘I will never be bothered by dragons again!’
        And so the gold coins stayed in the dragon’s lair for hundreds of years, each new king believing that the gold brought good luck to his people.
        The gold coins had stayed in the lair for all of that time until they were stolen, and it was while eating his dinner in front of the television that Adam first learned of the robbery.
        The reporter was at Wawel Castle. She was interviewing a tall policeman. The policeman said: ‘We believe that the thieves came into the castle during the day pretending to be tourists. They must have hidden in a dark corner of Smok’s lair and waited until the castle closed for the day. They then filled two large suitcases with as much gold as they could. This,’ he said, while pointing to a spot on the castle floor, ‘is all that remains of the precious gold coins.’
        The camera zoomed in on a few gold coins that were scattered on the floor.Standing next to the policeman was a very forlorn castle curator. He was shaking his head and murmuring something about it being very unlucky for the castle and for the city of Krakow.
        Adam’s father gasped: ‘All that treasure gone!’
        ‘What if another dragon comes along and sees that all the gold is missing?’ asked Adam. ‘They will know that Smok isn’t there anymore! The castle might be attacked and we would have a new dragon after all these years!’
        Basia, Adam’s older sister, chuckled to herself and said: ‘Well then, the King had better go to the bank and get some more gold coins out before it is too late.’
        The family laughed and returned to eating their delicious chicken soup. It seemed to Adam that nobody believed in dragons anymore, so maybe there was nothing to worry about after all.
        The next day, Adam woke up very early with the rest of his family. His parents and older brothers and sister were all going out to the fields to bring in the harvest. They would be gone for the whole day. The fields were far away from the farmhouse so they had to leave very early. It would be hard work for everybody.
        Every harvest, different members of the family would take it in turn to stay at home and look after the farm animals and prepare the barn to store the crops. It was also their job to prepare a feast for the hungry family to eat when they returned home. This year it was Adam’s turn.
        As his family left in the tractor, Adam gathered the food scraps for the farm animals and headed for the stables to feed the horses their hay. Then he milked the cows and walked them out to the field to graze.
        The next job was to clean out the barn.
        Adam opened the large doors and went inside. Once inside, Adam noticed a strange, golden light shimmering from the shadows towards the back of the barn. ‘I wonder what that could be,’ he thought, and went to investigate.
        As he approached the shimmering light, he could not believe what he saw on the floor of the barn ... Gold! A suitcase split open and it was full of gold! And beside that there was another case still closed. Adam was amazed. He was sure that this was the gold from Smok’s lair.
        \'The thieves must have been making their getaway and hidden the cases here so that the police would not find them,\’ he thought.
        Adam ran back to the house to tell his family what he had found. But once he reached the house, Adam remembered that his family was not there. So he ran to the phone and picked up the receiver ... then he paused again. Who was he going to call? He didn’t have the number for the castle. He could call the police, he thought, but they probably wouldn’t believe him. He put the phone down and thought for a moment.
        Suddenly Adam knew what he must do. He ran back to the barn and gathered the gold coins together and zipped up the suitcase. Then he fetched the wheelbarrow from the stable and, after much heaving and puffing, managed to get both cases inside the wheelbarrow.
        The next part of his plan he was really not looking forward to. He was going to have to take the bus to Krakow and return the gold himself. Adam had never in his life been on a bus, and he had never been to the big city of Krakow with its thousands of people and its noisy traffic and tall buildings. The thought made Adam very nervous, but the young boy was determined to be brave and return the gold to Smok’s lair no matter what. ‘After all,’ he reasoned, ‘somebody has to save the castle from dragons.’
        Adam took the jar containing his pocket money from under his bed and remembered to grab his coat from the hook behind the door. Then he locked the front door to the farmhouse and ran towards the barn to collect the wheelbarrow. Once he had gotten the hang of the wheelbarrow, which was very heavy indeed, he began on his journey toward the bus stop at the edge of the village.
        Adam had no idea when the next bus would be. He hoped he wouldn’t have to wait too long as he was already starting to feel very nervous about the journey and whether or not the driver would let him on with his wheelbarrow. Then the bus came around the bend in the road and stopped right there in front of him.
        The doors opened and the driver stared at the young boy and then at the wheelbarrow. Adam didn’t know what to do. After a moment the bus driver said: ‘Are you getting on or not?’
        ‘Can I bring my wheelbarrow?’ asked Adam.
        The driver paused for a moment. This wasn’t the first time he’d been asked by somebody from one of the villages if they could bring a wheelbarrow onto his bus. Luckily for Adam, the bus wasn’t already full of hay or live chickens, or even a sheep, which the driver had once let an old woman bring on board as long as she paid for two tickets.
        ‘Fine,’ said the driver. ‘Just hurry up.’
        After some more heaving and puffing, Adam managed to push the wheelbarrow onto the bus and quickly found himself a seat at the back.
        ‘Haven’t you forgotten something?’ shouted the driver from the front of the bus.
        Adam looked at the bus driver, trying to think what he could possibly mean.
        ‘You haven’t paid!’
        Of course! He had to buy a ticket. Adam jumped up from his seat and ran to the driver. He handed over his jar of pocket money and asked to be taken to Wawel Castle. The driver opened the jar and took out the money for a single trip to Krakow. He issued a ticket from the machine and passed it to Adam along with the jar containing the remainder of his pocket money. Adam walked back to his seat next to the wheelbarrow and sat down.
        As the bus drove out of the village, Adam concentrated on the cases in the wheelbarrow. He was afraid to look out of the window because he didn’t like the thought of leaving the village and travelling all by himself. Adam knew everybody in the village, but in a big city like Krakow he would not know a soul and might easily get lost.
        The bus travelled very slowly, stopping every few minutes to pick up more passengers.
        ‘This will take forever,’ thought Adam.
        Eventually, he grew bored of staring at the suitcases and decided to brave a look out of the window. He didn’t recognize where he was anymore, and he was afraid that he would not be able to find his way back home. The scenery had changed. It wasn’t green or spacious. The open fields that he was used to had been replaced by tall, grey buildings. Where before there were herds of cattle, now all he could see were crowds of people walking on massive stretches of pavement.
        Adam felt overwhelmed. ‘Where could all these people possibly have come from?’ he wondered.
        Suddenly, the bus came to a halt and the driver shouted back towards Adam that this was his stop. Wawel Castle! Finally he had arrived!
        Adam pushed the wheelbarrow up to the guards who were standing on either side of the giant gates. Beyond the gates, Adam could see the imposing castle. It was very big and even a bit scary.
        ‘Going on a holiday?’ asked one of the guards with a wry smile.
        ‘No,’ said Adam. ‘I have something that belongs to the castle and I am here to return it ... so that you don’t get any more dragons.'
            The guards looked down at the suitcases, then back at Adam. Just as they were about to tell Adam to run along, the curator appeared at the gates. Adam recognized him immediately from the news. The young boy seized his chance and opened one of the suitcases and took out a single gold coin. He held the coin up to the curator triumphantly and said: ‘I believe this belongs to you.’
The curator was overjoyed! He could not believe his ears when Adam told him how he had discovered the abandoned cases in his family’s barn. Adam also told the curator how he had gotten the wheelbarrow and his pocket money, and how he had travelled on the bus all the way to Krakow which he had never done before. Quite a crowd had gathered to hear Adam’s story and everybody was very impressed with the young boy.
Then the guards picked up the suitcases and, together with Adam, they followed the curator through the castle to Smok’s lair.
Adam had never been inside a real castle before. He had never even been outside a real castle before. He looked on in wonder as he was led through huge rooms adorned with fancy silks and old paintings. Every room seemed bigger and fancier than the last.
The convoy of people eventually reached the entrance to Smok’s lair and carefully descended the steps. The deeper they went, the darker and colder it got, but still they went on until the narrow stairwell opened out into the lair itself.
‘It looks just like it did on the television yesterday,’ Adam said, to nobody in particular.
The guards opened the suitcases and Adam and the curator both grabbed big handfuls of the shiny gold coins and began throwing them across the floor in sheer delight. The curator was laughing out loud with a mixture of joy and relief. And Adam was laughing because he was so proud that he had succeeded in his mission to return the gold and keep the castle safe.
‘No more dragons!’ he thought.
Once all of the coins were back where they belonged, Adam started to say goodbye because he had a long journey ahead of him. But the curator was not about to let the young boy depart in such a manner.
‘You really are the bravest boy in the whole city,’ said the curator. ‘You should stay a while so that we might thank you properly.’
Adam wanted very much to stay, but he was thinking about his home and his family and the long bus journey ahead. He said: ‘I would like to stay but I haven't prepared the barn for the harvest or the meal for the evening. My family will be wondering where I am and they'll be angry that I have not done all of my chores.’
‘Don't you worry,’ said the curator. ‘You have done a wonderful thing for the city. Now it is our turn to do something for you. Follow me!’
And with that, the curator led Adam up the dark stairwell and out across the main hall of the castle. Along the way, the old man issued instructions to the guards who then barked instructions into their radios. Suddenly the castle seemed to be alive with activity.
By the time Adam and the curator reached the castle gates, there was a shiny black limousine and a very large truck awaiting their arrival.
Castle guards, in their royal red and gold uniforms, were boarding the back of the truck carrying an array of large and small boxes. A very smartly dressed chauffeur opened the door to the limousine and tipped his hat as Adam got inside.
The journey back to Adam’s village was much quicker than his original bus journey into the city, and he didn’t even have to spend any of his pocket money!
In no time at all they had reached the village and were soon turning off of the main road towards Adam’s home.
As the limousine drove up the gravel path towards the house, Adam could see his family standing in the yard. They all looked very worried and very confused at the sight of the limousine and the truck and the guards in their red and gold uniforms.
When the convoy stopped and Adam got out of the limousine, the whole family rushed towards him: all of them were speaking at once so that Adam found it difficult to understand them and more impossible still to answer their questions.
Just as Adam was busy apologising for not completing his chores, the curator stepped in and explained how Adam had returned the missing gold to the castle.
‘A very brave boy you have here,’ said the curator as he introduced himself to the family. ‘All of us at the castle are so very grateful.’
Adam’s mother and father were beaming with pride by the time the curator had finished recounting their son’s brave deeds.
Then the curator said: ‘I understand that there are a few things that still need doing around the farm. Please don’t worry about a thing.’ And with that he turned to the guards and nodded.
The guards instantly divided themselves into three groups. The first ran to the barn and began clearing space for the harvested crops, while another group began unloading the crops from the trailer. The third group ran to the house and brought the family dining table out into the farmyard and laid the table with a fine cloth, plates, glasses, and fancy silver cutlery from the castle.
Huge platters of delicious smelling foods were carried from the back of the truck and placed on the table.
Adam’s family seated themselves at the table and the curator proposed a toast in Adam’s honour. They were surrounded by a guard of honour and Adam thought to himself: ‘This is what is must be like to be royalty.’
The family laughed and ate together, and all the while Adam told them about the tall buildings in Krakow and the crowds of people and the castle and the limousine ride.
It really had been an incredible day. And as Adam enjoyed the wonderful feast, he told himself that he was sure he would never forget his adventure. But he was also very pleased that next year it would be his brother’s turn to stay at home while Adam joined his family in the fields for the harvest.
        </string>

    <string name="story2"> Each evening Ali Baba went out to gather twigs and branches for his wife so that she had enough firewood to cook the stew for dinner.

One day, Ali Baba went further than usual to hunt for fallen branches beneath the trees that grew beside the rocky cliffs near the high hills.

Suddenly, he heard a great clatter of hooves on the rocky path. He was afraid. He climbed the nearest tree and hid among the leaves.

He was well hidden but was able to peer between the leaves. He was astonished to see a long line of men on horseback, riding one behind the other.

Ali Baba counted them as they rode beneath the tree where he hid.

‘One … two … three … four,’ and many, many more, until he had counted forty.

Finally, the forty riders reached a cliff face. They dismounted and removed the saddlebags from their horses’ backs. Ali Baba noticed that the bags were bulging.

‘Perhaps the bags are full of treasure,’ thought Ali Baba. ‘These men are thieves and robbers. Maybe they are about to hide their loot.’

The thieves lined up behind their leader. They were right in front of the steep rocky cliff.

‘How silly!’ Ali Baba thought. ‘There is nowhere to hide treasure here.’

At that moment, one of the riders spoke loudly.

\'Open Sesame!\' he cried.

Suddenly, a secret door in the rock opened. The forty riders entered a hidden cave. They were going to hide the treasure they had stolen.

When they were all inside, the leader shouted, ‘Close Sesame!’

The secret door closed again with the thieves hidden safely inside.

Ali Baba waited, hidden in his treetop until the riders came out of the cave again. He counted carefully to make sure that they were all out.

‘One … two … three … four,’ and many, many, many more until he reached thirty-nine.

Last of all came the leader. When he stood outside the cave, he again said, ‘Close Sesame!’

The secret rock door closed.

Ali Baba peered through the leaves. He was amazed to see how perfectly the door fitted into the rock.

The thieves put the empty saddlebags over their horses. Then they set off, one by one.

Ali Baba counted to make sure that they had all gone. ‘One … two … three … four,’ and many, many, many more until he reached forty. Then he listened until he could no longer hear any hooves clattering – he was safe!

Ali Baba climbed down the tree and walked up to the rocky cliff. He was curious to discover if the magic door would open for him if he said the special word. Would he be brave enough to try?

Ali Baba stood there. He looked at the rocky cliff. He thought about all the treasure in the cave, and he thought about the forty thieves. He couldn’t hear anything at all.

At last, he decided, ‘I must be safe now. So I shall be brave and say the magic words out loud.’

Then Ali Baba went close to the rocky cliff.

‘Open Sesame!’ he said. The door opened.

Ali Baba could see steps leading down. Little lamps of burning oil lit the stairway. He was just about to descend the steps when he remembered. The leader of the thieves had spoken two words to close the magic door.

Ali Baba decided that he should shut the magic door too. It would not be a good idea for anyone else to see the entrance to the cave of treasure.

‘Close Sesame!’ he cried, and the magic door slid shut.

After that, Ali Baba crept down the stone steps until he reached the treasure cave. He gazed all around in amazement. There were thousands of sparkling jewels in great heaps: diamonds, rubies, emeralds and every other sort of precious gem. Then there was gold! Ali Baba’s eyes grew wide in wonder when he saw the vast piles of gold coins.

However, Ali Baba was not greedy. He didn’t want the diamonds, or the rubies or the emeralds. Although Ali Baba was a poor man, he had no desire to take all the gold coins. He wanted just one little gold coin. It would be enough to buy food for himself and his family.

So Ali Baba took one small coin and ran back up the stone steps. At the top, he took a deep breath.

\'Open Sesame!\' he gasped.

Immediately the magic door opened. With a sigh of relief, Ali Baba hurried outside. Then he turned and called out the magic words.

‘Close Sesame!’

The door slid shut. Ali Baba was safe.

However, there was something Ali Baba did not know. His brother, Kassim, had also come to find firewood. Kassim had seen Ali Baba come out of the cave and speak some magic words. He had seen the magic rock door close.

‘Oh, Ali Baba! My brother! What is this magic that I have just seen?’

Ali Baba told his brother everything. He warned Kassim that the forty thieves might return any minute. So they both gathered up armfuls of firewood, and they hurried home, each to their own house.

Ali Baba was pleased to have his one small gold coin. His wife was also pleased to have one small gold coin. However, in the house next door, Kassim was not pleased. He was greedy. Kassim told his wife all about his younger brother’s adventure. His wife was not pleased. She was just as greedy as her husband.

‘Kassim,’ she said. ‘Go back to the rocky cliffs and say the magic words. Go down into the cave and fetch me some jewels and gold coins. I want lots of large gold coins.’ She gave him a large bag to carry all the treasure.

Kassim did as his wife had said. He took the bag and ran back to the rocks.

In front of the cliff, he said the magic words. ‘Open Sesame!’

When the secret door opened, Kassim hurried inside.

He spoke the magic words to close the door. ‘Close Sesame!’

The little oil lamps were still alight. Kassim was able to see the stairway that led down to the treasure cave. He ran down the stone steps as fast as he could.

When Kassim saw all the sparkling jewels and glistening gold, his eyes lit up with greed. He began stuffing gems and coins into his bag. It was soon filled to the brim; there was no room for any more treasure.

Kassim became so excited that something dreadful happened. He forgot the magic words! Kassim ran up the stone steps and stood in front of the magic door.

‘Open Barley!’ he cried.

Nothing happened.

‘Open Oats!’

Nothing happened.

Kassim was worried.

‘I know it was something to eat,’ he said to himself. So he tried everything he could think of.

‘Open Wheat! Open Rye! Open Pumpkin! Open Melon!’

At that moment, something even more dreadful happened. The magic door slid open, and there stood the thieves who had stolen the treasure.

‘Robbers!’ squealed Kassim. Before he had time to count them, the leader pulled out his sword. He threatened Kassim with his sharp curved blade.

The thieves’ leader saw that Kassim’s was bag bulging with their treasure.

He poked his sword into Kassim, and the greedy man fell down, never to move again.

That night Kassim’s wife became worried when her husband didn’t return home with any treasure. She went next door to Ali Baba.

Ali Baba listened to her story, and he feared the worst. ‘I had better go and find him,’ he said to her.

He was afraid that the thieves had found Kassim.

Ali Baba took a lantern and went up into the rocky mountains to look for his brother. On the ground in front of the hidden cave lay Kassim’s dead body.

Ali Baba lifted his brother and carried him back home so that the family could bury him properly.

The next day the thieves returned to their hidden cave with more treasure that they had stolen. The thieves’ leader expected to see the lifeless body of the man he had killed – but it wasn’t there!

‘Stop! Wait!’ the leader cried. He bent down to study the ground, and he was able to see the tracks from where the body had been taken.

‘We must hide our treasure quickly,’ he cried out to the others. ‘I must follow these tracks. It seems as though someone else knows of our secret hiding place. Go home and sharpen your swords. Be ready for a fight tomorrow. Hire a large cart and a strong donkey. Buy thirty-nine large olive oil jars that are big enough to hide inside. Make a hole in each lid so that you can get fresh air into the jar to breathe. Make sure everything is ready and then meet me here tomorrow at daybreak.’

While the thirty-nine robbers did as he had said, their leader followed the tracks all the way to Ali Baba’s house.

‘When I come back tomorrow,’ said the thief to himself. ‘I shall pretend to be a seller of fine quality olive oil. I shall park my cart of olive oil jars in this man’s yard, and I’ll go and knock on his door. When I shout, ‘Olive oil!’ my thieves will come rushing in with their swords drawn, ready for a fight.’

Little did the man know, Ali Baba’s maid, Morgiana, had come quietly out of the back door of the house. She overheard every word that the man muttered to himself.

He continued talking to himself. ‘In my cart, I shall have thirty-nine olive oil jars. In each jar, I shall have a man armed with a sharp sword.’ The man gave an evil laugh. ‘When the man inside opens the door he won’t know what hit him!’

Morgiana crept back into the house to tell Ali Baba what she had overheard. She began by saying, ‘I have a plan …’ and then she told Ali Baba what her plan was.

The next day, early in the morning, the thieves met up with their leader. There were thirty-nine enormous jars on the cart. A man hid in each empty olive oil jar. Their leader put a lid on the top of each jar.

A sturdy donkey pulled the heavy cart to Ali Baba’s house. The thieves’ leader parked his cart in Ali Baba’s yard. Then he went and knocked on the door.

Ali Baba opened the door.

‘You’re an olive oil merchant?’ he said. ‘Splendid, that is just what we need. I shall buy a jar from you. I will pay you a good price, but first, come in and have a drink with us.’

The man happily accepted a drink, but he didn’t know that Morgiana had put sleeping powder into the liquid.

Morgiana crept into the yard. She was carrying a dish of soft cheese, and she used it to plug all the breathing holes in the jars. When the thieves had no more fresh air to breathe, they collapsed into the bottom of their jars.

Morgiana then ran to the house of the village Sheikh. She knocked politely on the door and told her story as soon as she was taken inside.

‘Evil men came to the house of Ali Baba. They came armed with sharp swords to kill him, but I have managed to trick them and trap them. They are the ones who have been robbing the travellers on the road to our village. They have been stealing from people in all the towns and villages near here.’

The Sheikh called on the guards. They went to Ali Baba’s house and captured all forty thieves.

‘My dungeon is deep and has many chambers,’ said the Sheikh. ‘There is plenty of space to keep them there for a long, long time. Bread, water and a hard stone floor – that’s good enough for them.’

Then the guards went with Ali Baba to bring all the treasure back to the village. The Sheikh tried to return all the jewels and all the money to their rightful owners. In the end, there was still some treasure left over. So the Sheikh shared what remained with Ali Baba and Morgiana.

Ali Baba’s son fell in love with Morgiana. She eventually married him, and so this story had a happy ending for Ali Baba and his family.
    </string>

    <string name="story3"> Many centuries ago, a nobleman lived in Krakow. His name was Jan Twardowski. He was an educated man, and he loved books and science. He was especially interested in magic and alchemy, but after many years of research, he understood that witchcraft is impossible without using supernatural forces.

        One day, Master Twardowski found spells in his library books that would help him contact spirits. He completed the rituals in the books. When he had finished, a tall slim creature appeared in his room. It was the Devil himself. He had small black horns on his head, long sharp claws and hooves instead of feet.

        The Devil looked at the man and grinned, revealing his sharp teeth.

        “How can I serve you, Master Twardowski?” asked the Devil.

        Master Twardowski told the Devil about his research on magic and his wish to make real spells that worked. The Devil assured him that his dreams could soon come true. All Master Twardowski had to do was sign a contract agreeing to give his soul to the Devil.

        Master Twardowski knew that the contract was a trap. It would lock him in Hell for eternity.

        “Your offer is very generous,” he said to the Devil. “I’ll soon be making a pilgrimage to Rome. You can have my soul as soon as I arrive there.”

        The Devil did not object to this addition and was pleased with the prospect of gaining a new soul. He did not know, however, that Twardowski did not intend to visit Rome at all.

        Both parties signed the contract. From that moment on, the Devil was bound to serve Master Twardowski in making his magic possible.

        The Devil knew that human souls are, after all, selfish and greedy. He expected that Master Twardowski would use his new magical powers for evil purposes. However, to his surprise, Twardowski used magic to do good. He helped people and animals in any way he could. Soon, Master Twardowski became famous across the whole country. One day, the king himself called Twardowski for help.

        Weeks, months and years had passed since the contract was signed. Master Twardowski, however, did not even think about going to Rome. So the Devil was angry, and he kept thinking and thinking until he had an idea.

        The Devil transformed himself into a peasant and visited Master Twardowski. He begged for help to heal his sick mother. Twardowski, of course, agreed to go with the peasant to a nearby inn where the sick woman was supposed to be waiting for them.

        As soon as they passed through the doorway of the inn, the Devil transformed back to his proper form. He started to laugh loudly.

        “I have you now, Twardowski! Your soul belongs to me! We’re in Rome, just as the contract says! That’s the name of this inn!”

        Master Twardowski was shocked and did not know what to do. The Devil lifted him high above the ground, then high above the city. They were floating in the sky when Master Twardowski started to pray. As he prayed, the Devil’s powers weakened until finally, he couldn’t carry Twardowski anymore.

        The Devil lost his powers as they were flying over the moon. Rumour has it that he dropped Master Twardowski there. The man fell and lives there still. He looks down and watches over his beloved country and its people, making sure they are well./string>
    </string>
    <string name="story4">
A long time ago, in a village not too far from a stream, a kind-hearted soldier was trudging down a dusty lane. His movements were slow as he had been walking the whole day. He would have loved nothing more than to eat a nice, hot meal. As he came across a quaint little house on the side of the road, he thought to himself, ‘The person who lives here must have some extra food to share with a hungry traveller like me; I think I’ll go and ask.’

And so the soldier walked up the cobbled path towards the wooden door, past the garden full of growing cabbages, potatoes, onions and carrots. Once he reached the front of the house, he raised his hand to knock when the door suddenly opened. On the other side stood an old man. His hands were on his hips and he had a frown on his face.

‘What do you want?’ said the old man, rudely. Still the soldier smiled at him.

‘Hello there, I am a soldier from a village not too far from here. I have come to you to ask if you have any food you would be able to spare.’

The old man looked the soldier up and down and replied very bluntly. ‘No. Now go away.’

The soldier was not put off by this – he smiled once again and nodded his head. ‘I see, I am only asking so I will have a few more ingredients for my stone soup, but I guess I will have to have it plain. Just as tasty though!’

The old man scrunched up his eyebrows. ‘Stone soup?’ he asked.

‘Yes sir,’ the soldier replied, ‘now if you’ll excuse me…’

The soldier walked to the middle of the path and hauled an iron cauldron from his belongings. Once he had filled it with water he began to build a fire under it. Then with great ceremony, he drew an ordinary-looking stone from a silk bag and gently dropped it into the water.

The old man watched all of this from his window, bewildered.

‘Stone soup?’ he asked himself. ‘Surely there is no such thing!’

And after a while of watching the soldier stir the water with a small stick, the old man walked out and asked the soldier, ‘What are you doing?’

The soldier took a sniff of the steam coming out of his pot and licked his lips in anticipation, ‘Ah, there’s nothing I like more than a tasty bit of stone soup.’ He then looked up at the old man, adding ‘Of course, stone soup with a bit of salt and pepper is hard to beat.’

Hesitantly, the old man went inside and returned with salt and pepper, slowly handing it over to the soldier.

‘Perfect!’ cried the soldier as he sprinkled them into the pot. He stirred it once more before looking over to the old man again, ‘But you know, I once tasted this amazing stone soup with cabbage.’

The old man then approached his cabbage plants and picked the ripest cabbage, handing it to the soldier.

‘Oh, how wonderful!’ the soldier exclaimed as he chopped the cabbage up and dropped it into the pot.

He took a deep sniff of the pot and said to the old man, ‘You know, this would be a soup fit for a king with a few carrots.’

The old man said thoughtfully, ‘I think I can find some carrots,’ and he went over to his carrots and picked a handful.

The soldier was delighted when he was presented with the carrots; he chopped them up and stirred the pot once again.

And so it went on. The old man began to grow delighted at the smell from the pot as he brought onions, potatoes, and beef and so on. The soldier himself also added things like mushrooms and barley from his own bag, until he declared the soup was ready.

The old man smiled at the soldier when he offered half of the soup to him.

‘Why don’t you come inside? I have some fresh bread brought straight from the bakery this morning that would taste delicious with the stone soup,’ he said kindly.

And so the old man and the soldier shared a wonderful meal together. The soldier brought out a carton of milk from his bag and together they shared that too. The old man agreed with the soldier that the soup was better than anything she had tasted before.

It wasn’t until the soldier had given him the silk bag containing the stone that the old man realised the truth. It was never the stone that had created the delicious soup. Rather, by working together and being generous, both he and the soldier had been able to create a scrumptious meal that they could share between them.
    </string>

        <string name="story5">
St John’s Night is the shortest night of the year. It is on this night that the legendary Fern Flower blooms somewhere in the forest. The golden flower, with its mysterious glowing centre, blooms for only one night until dawn. When the first rooster crows, the flower disappears and will not bloom again until the following year.

It is said that the path to the flower is protected by the trees and mystical creatures of the forest so that only the most courageous and noble young man might find it. The flower possesses the power to fulfil wishes, and whoever finds this flower will have all of his wishes granted; but he will not be allowed to share his wealth with others or he will lose everything.

*

Long ago, there was a young boy called Jack, but everybody in the village called him The Curious One because Jack always wanted things which appeared beyond the grasp of others. He did not care about things which he could get simply by reaching out his hand. Instead, he wanted things which required a great effort to obtain.

Once, when everybody in the village was sitting around the bonfire, the elder of the village told the story of the Fern Flower. The woman was very old and had travelled all over the world and seen many strange things, so Jack listened to the story very carefully.

The young boy was fascinated and promised himself then and there that he would find the flower and make all of his wishes come true. It did not matter that the Fern Flower bloomed only once a year. If Jack did not find the flower on the first year, then he would keep looking year after year.

When St John’s Night finally arrived, Jack dressed in his best clothes and went into the forest to seek out the mythical flower. Jack knew the paths and the trees of the forest very well, but on this night he did not recognise a single thing. The trees appeared much taller, and their branches and trunks stretched out in such a way that he could not always walk around them. The bushes were thicker and spikier, and the pathways were all darker and scarier.

Jack kept walking despite all of the obstacles in his way – despite the darkness and the terrifying blue, red, yellow and green eyes watching from the darkness. Jack walked on because he knew that the strangeness of the forest, and the scary eyes in the darkness, were all there to prevent him from finding the mythical Fern Flower.

The pine trees were tall and wide and caused Jack to make very slow progress. The bushes were so thick that he had to hack at them with his hands and feet in order to continue on his journey.

Then he came across a pine tree that was so tall it seemed to stretch up into the sky, and so wide it seemed to him as if it would take forever to walk around its trunk. When eventually he had gotten to the other side of the tree, he noticed that it was not so tall and wide after all, but rather another trick of the mysterious forest.

Some time later, Jack came across a marsh in the middle of the gloomiest, dampest part of the forest. There was no way around the marsh, and when Jack tried to put his foot into the water he almost sank to the bottom. Eventually the young boy noticed very small clumps of grass dotted here and there across the length of the marsh. He decided that this was the only way to cross the boggy water, so he took a deep breath and jumped from one clump to the next until he had crossed over to the other side.



Jack continued on his winding journey through the forest until he came across a massive fern in the middle of a clearing. He noticed a tiny, radiant flower growing on a leaf of the fern. Jack had never seen anything so beautiful. The flower had five golden petals, and in its centre something like an eye that flickered and glowed against the darkness of the night. Jack also thought he heard the distant sound of laughter, but told himself that it was just another trick of the forest.

He reached out very slowly, but just as he was about to touch the flower, the rooster crowed and there was a bright flash of light and the flower disappeared.

In the darkness Jack fell asleep, and the next time he awoke his mother was standing over him and he noticed that he was lying in his own bed. Jack’s mother looked very worried and explained how she had found him asleep in the middle of the forest that morning.

The young boy felt ashamed that he had failed, but he never told his mother or his friends what he had been doing in the forest that night because he was afraid they would not believe him. Instead, Jack made a silent promise to himself that he would try again the following year.

Jack thought about the flower all year long until St John’s Night finally arrived again. As the villagers gathered around the fires, he dressed in his best clothes and went into the dark forest in search of the flower. This time the trees were even wider and taller. There were huge, slippery stones on the forest floor, and thick ferns, some much taller than the young boy. Once again, the strange eyes looked at him from out of the darkness, but Jack continued on his search.

After many hours, he saw something glowing in the distance. As he got closer he knew that it was the same flower with its five golden petals and the amazing glowing eye at its centre.

Jack approached the flower in awe, but before he managed to touch it, the rooster crowed and the flower disappeared just as before. Jack was so tired after his adventure that he instantly fell fast asleep and experienced a strange dream in which the eye of the flower looked right at him. The flower asked the young boy, ‘Are you ready to give up yet?’

When eventually he awoke from the dream, he promised himself that next St John’s Night, the flower would be his for certain.

The year passed very slowly, but eventually St John’s Night arrived, and again Jack dressed in his best clothes and set off into the forest.



This time the forest looked normal, just like it did in the daytime. Jack looked for the flower but could not find it anywhere. Then, quite suddenly, he noticed it, right there at his feet: the flower with five golden petals and the mysterious, glowing eye at its centre. Jack reached out and finally touched the mythical flower before the rooster could crow.

The flower burnt his fingers as if the petals were on fire! But Jack did not let go. As he put the flower inside his jacket, he heard a quiet voice say to him: ‘Now you can have anything in the world you have ever wanted, but you may never share your happiness with another soul.’

But Jack was too excited to hear the words of warning as he felt the flower laying down its delicate roots into his young heart. The Fern Flower was finally his, and he was going to have his every wish fulfilled.



When Jack reached the edge of the forest he should have been able to see his cottage, but instead he saw a palace in the middle of a large kingdom. This was something Jack had always wished for: to live in a palace and be ruler of his own kingdom. But there was also a carriage with six white horses waiting to take him to his new palace.

There were many servants inside the palace, but his family and friends were not there, nor anybody from his old village on the edge of the forest.

The young boy had a very comfortable bed and mountains of gold in the vaults of his palace. He often thought that he might send some of this gold to his family, but then he would remember how it was forbidden for him to share any of his wealth and happiness with another soul, even his family. If he did this, then everything would disappear and he would be poor again. And so the young boy decided that he must keep everything for himself, and if anybody else ever needed anything then they would just have to search for the Fern Flower as he had done.

Jack lived what many would call a happy life, but although the young boy had everything his heart desired, he was very bored and so became a cruel and wicked king who treated his subjects unfairly.

One day, he decided to take the carriage and visit his old village because he missed his mother very much. When he arrived at the little cottage on the edge of the forest, Jack’s mother observed the six white horses with fear in her eyes. He stepped down from the carriage with open arms but his mother did not recognise him. She said, ‘My son Jack is dead. If he were alive he would never leave his family. If he ever found the Fern Flower he would not keep such wealth and happiness for himself. He would share it with his family and friends.’

Jack wanted to show his mother how much he longed to share everything he had with her, but each time he reached for the gold in his pocket he remembered that he would lose everything if he were to share with others.

With this realisation, Jack’s heart turned to stone and he ordered his carriage to take him back to the palace.



Upon his return, he ordered his subjects and his servants to entertain him. He got drunk on wine and tried to forget about his old life in the little village. But no matter what he did, Jack could never forget the look of sadness on his mother’s face.

One year later, Jack decided to visit his family again. This time, when the carriage pulled up outside of his home, his mother did not come out to greet him. Instead, his brother approached the carriage. When Jack asked about his mother, his brother told him that she was very ill and that his father had gone.

Jack entered the cottage and saw his mother laid out on her tiny, uncomfortable bed. She looked very sick and could not even sit up to face her son. Jack felt a great guilt and fear come over him. He could not stand the thought of losing his mother. He wanted to reach into his pocket for the gold that might help his family, but again he remembered that he would lose everything if he were to share his wealth with others.

‘My mother is old and will not suffer for long,’ he reasoned. ‘I am young, and if I give up everything now I will suffer for many years.’

Jack turned his back on his family and returned to the palace. But as hard as the young boy tried to forget his family, he was haunted by images of his sick mother and his poor brother. He tried to ignore his feelings but was unable to enjoy his wealth or his beautiful palace.



It was during these long, lonely nights in the palace that Jack realised how useless his wealth really was if he could not share it with friends and family.

As time went by, Jack lost weight and his health became very poor. He was always miserable and his vast wealth no longer seemed to matter.

The young man awoke one day and knew that he must return home to his family and his friends. He ordered his carriage to take him right away to his old house in the village on the edge of the forest. But when Jack arrived back at his old home, nobody came out to greet him.

Jack stepped down from the carriage and approached the little cottage. He looked through a tiny window, hoping to see his family inside, but the cottage was empty.

It was then that an old beggar approached Jack and told him, ‘Nobody lives in that cottage anymore. They all died of disease and hunger, for they were too poor to buy food and were unable to send for a doctor.’

Jack began to cry over the loss of his family. He was the boy who could have anything he wished for, but what good was that if he did not have his family or friends around to share in his happiness? Jack wished he was dead because he could not bear the thought of being alone any longer.

Suddenly the ground opened up beneath his feet and Jack vanished into the darkness below, the mythical Fern Flower still clinging to his cold heart after fulfilling the young boy’s final wish.

The Fern Flower has never been found by another, and Jack, the young boy whom the villagers once called The Curious One, has never been seen again.
        </string>

    <string name="story6">
Long ago, a young boy named Lutek lived in Warsaw. He was a shoemaker, and he worked in one of the factories in the Old Town. Lutek was penniless and lived on what he managed to earn from the foreman.

In the evenings, Lutek often sat at the inn and listened to the exciting stories of older residents. He liked the tales so much that he often imagined being a brave warrior on the battlefield or a wealthy merchant travelling across distant lands. One evening, he heard the quiet conversations of the masters.

“Apparently on Tamka Street, in the basement of the Ostrogski Castle, there is a golden duck.” Master Jan whispered mysteriously.

“I heard that it is a beautiful bird, but also very crafty and dangerous,” Master Bartłomiej added.

“Why is it dangerous? How can a duck be dangerous?” others asked.

“Looking for the duck can get you lost in an underground basement. You might never return to the surface. They say that many have already tried and never returned,” Master Jan replied.

“What if someone meets the duck?” asked young Staś. He was the son of one of the masters.

“Then the duck will make him rich forever,” replied the masters.

Lutek heard these words and immediately ran out of the inn. He headed straight to Tamka Street. He reached the castle and found the entrance to the underground basement. It was dark, cold and damp.

The boy walked the corridors for a long time. At first, he was looking for the duck and then looking for the way back. He was so tired and cold that he lost all hope of returning home.

Eventually, Lutek found himself in a large chamber with a high vault, decorated with gold. Within the vault, there was a beautiful blue lake on which swam the golden duck.

“Hello, Lutek,” she said in a human voice. “You found me, so you deserve the prize. I will make you rich. Take this pouch; there are one hundred golden ducats inside. Buy whatever you want, but you have to spend it all in one day, and you cannot share it with anyone. If you do not meet these conditions, you will remain poor forever.”

Lutek grabbed the pouch and headed back. This time the corridors seemed brighter and easier to find, so he quickly got to the top.

Warsaw was waking up. Shops were slowly opening, and people were coming out to the streets.

“At last, I am rich!” thought Lutek. He ran towards the market. First, he bought all the delicacies he had ever wanted. Then he went to the tailor and dressed in the most expensive outfit. It was decorated with precious stones and gold, paired with leather shoes with golden spurs.

Then he went to the best restaurant and ordered the most expensive dishes to eat and the noblest honey water to drink. Many people introduced themselves and engaged in polite conversation. They were counting on a donation from such a rich young man. However, Lutek did not give anyone a penny.

In the afternoon, he bought the most magnificent horse. At the jeweller, he ordered a gold ring with the largest diamond. In the evening he went to the theatre, where he sat in the prince’s lodge.

As the evening grew dark, Lutek’s purse was still half full. The stores were slowly closing. Lutek was too full to eat any more. He wondered what else he could spend money on when he heard a voice:

“Noble sir, please help an old beggar. The war took everything I had.”

He looked around and saw the hunched figure of an old man in the shadows. The rags he was wearing had indeed once been a beautiful soldier’s uniform.

Lutek reached into his pocket and pulled out a handful of ducats. The moment he handed them to the beggar, a bright light shone right next to him.

He heard the voice of the golden duck: “You have not met my conditions! You will always be a poor shoemaker!”

Lutek looked at the happy old man.

“Good!” he said. “I could not live like that anyway, because I would never be truly happy. Money does not give you happiness unless you have someone to share it with.”


    </string>

<string name="story7">
Once upon a time, there was a beautiful jamun tree that grew by the side of a river. A monkey lived in this tree; a happy and generous monkey who loved to eat the sweet jamun fruit that grew in abundance on the branches of the tree.

One day, a hungry crocodile approached the monkey and asked, ‘May I try some of the fruit from your tree?’

The monkey agreed without hesitation and quickly threw some of the sweet fruit down to the hungry crocodile. The crocodile ate the dark berries and found that he liked them very much. And so he returned to the tree the following day and asked the monkey again if he might try some of the sweet fruit from the jamun tree. And once again the monkey agreed to share his fruit.

The crocodile returned to the tree each day for many weeks and soon the two animals became very good friends.

One day, the crocodile asked the monkey, ‘Might I have some of the fruit from your tree to take home to my wife?’

Because they were such good friends the monkey agreed to give the crocodile some fruit to take home. The crocodile thanked the monkey and took the sweet fruit home to his wife. But the wife was not a nice crocodile, she was a witch crocodile and she was forever scheming and plotting against the other animals of the forest.

‘Where did you get this lovely fruit?’ the wife asked her husband.

‘I have a dear friend,’ replied the crocodile, ‘a monkey who lives in the jamun tree on the other side of the river. He gives me the fruit each day.’

The wife – being a witch, and an evil witch at that – thought for a moment and then said to her husband, ‘If the monkey lives in the jamun tree and eats the sweet fruit all day long, then imagine how sweet his heart must taste! I want this monkey’s heart to eat and you will get it for me.’

‘I cannot imagine such a terrible thing!’ replied the husband crocodile. ‘The monkey is my friend and I do not want you to eat his heart!’

The cunning wife thought again and then replied, ‘I do not believe that you are getting this lovely fruit from a monkey. I think that you are seeing another crocodile behind my back, a pretty crocodile. You are cheating on me, I know it!’

The husband protested his innocence and grew very sad at his wife’s accusations. He decided that it was best to stay away from the monkey and the jamun tree in the hopes that his life would return to normal and his wife would forget all about her evil plan.

But the weeks passed slowly and the crocodile’s wife continued to accuse him of cheating on her even though she knew this not to be the truth.

‘I know that if there really was a monkey who lived in the jamun tree then you would help me catch him and eat his heart,’ she would say to her husband. ‘That is what you would do if you loved me.’

Eventually the poor crocodile was convinced to go and see the monkey and try to catch him so that his wife might eat his heart.

When he arrived at the tree the following evening he felt very guilty. The monkey looked down and asked, ‘Where have you been all these weeks, dear friend? I have missed you very much.’

The crocodile replied as his wife had instructed. ‘I have been arguing with my poor wife. She very much wants you to come to dinner so that she can thank you for the jamun fruit, but we live on the other side of the river. You cannot swim. If you try to cross the river, then you will surely drown and I certainly do not want that.’

‘But you can carry me on your back across the river,’ said the monkey. ‘That way I will be able to come to dinner and finally meet you wife.’

The crocodile agreed but he was very sad that he was tricking his friend. The monkey, not knowing his fate, jumped down from the jamun tree and climbed onto the crocodile’s back. Then the two friends slipped into the water and began to cross the river towards the crocodile’s home.

As he was swimming across the river, the crocodile realised that he was unable to trick the monkey.

‘I am not telling you the truth,’ said the crocodile. ‘My wife is an evil witch and she wants to eat your heart. I am very, very sorry.’

The monkey grew scared, but he was a clever monkey and so he replied very calmly, ‘Oh, why did you not tell me that before, dear friend? I have left my heart in the jamun tree. We must swim back and I will get my heart for your wife.’

The crocodile was quite surprised that the monkey was so willing to give up his heart, but he quickly turned around and swam back towards the riverbank.

As soon as they reached the jamun tree, the monkey jumped from the crocodile’s back and clambered up the tree as fast as he could until he reached the highest branch. When he was sure that he was safe, he looked down at the crocodile.

‘You are a silly crocodile. My heart is beating in my chest where it has always been beating and your evil wife will never have a chance to eat it! And we will never speak again because you betrayed me! Now go away!’

The crocodile had a great deal of time to reflect upon his actions as he swam home to his wife. He felt guilty and sad for betraying his friend and he regretted his actions very much.

As soon as he arrived home his wife asked, ‘Where is the monkey?’

‘I am afraid that the monkey tricked me and now he will never come down from his tree,’ replied the crocodile.

But the wife was not convinced by her husband’s story and she kicked him out of their home and told him never to return for as long as he lived.

The crocodile turned his back on his wife and began to swim down river, away from everything he had ever known. He was sad and lonely and he did not know where he was going, but he also knew that he had sealed his own fate the moment he betrayed his good friend the monkey.

‘This is what I deserve,’ thought the sad crocodile as he swam down river into a dark and gloomy night.
</string>

    <string name="story8">
There was once a farmer who had two sons.

The older son was selfish and greedy, while the younger son was kind and generous.

When the farmer died, the older brother took all of his land for himself leaving the younger brother with nothing except a basket and a sharp knife with which he could cut firewood.

He would go into the forest and chop wood and sell it in exchange for a little rice in the marketplace.

He was poor. He had nothing.

One day, the young brother climbed through the forest to the top of the mountain. There he sat upon a rock gazing out towards the west where the sun was setting.

As he sat there all alone he felt a rush of air from above and he looked and there was a bright bird flying down towards him. It had a huge wingspan.

He felt the beating of air, the rush of air. Then it landed next to him.

‘Why do you sit here all alone?’

‘I am poor. I have nothing.’

‘Is this true or is this false?’

‘It is true, I am poor. I have nothing.’

‘Then climb on my back,’ said the mighty bird, ‘and I will carry you to the Island of the Sun.

There you may take one piece of gold before I bring you back.’

He climbed onto the back of the bird and the bird took off.

Away from the mountain the great bird flew.

Over the forest the great bird flew.

Over the waters the great bird flew.

To the Island of the Sun the great bird flew.

As the bird landed, the sun set behind the island which glittered brightly, and the boy took one piece of gold.

He put it in his basket and climbed onto the back of the great bird.

Away from the island the great bird flew.

Over the waters the great bird flew.

Over the forest the great bird flew.

Back to the mountain the great bird flew.

The young brother took that piece of gold and went down out of the forest, and there he bought a small piece of land.

There he reared pigs, cows, and a few hens.

He lived well. He worked hard.

But one day his older brother came.

‘Where did you find this wealth, this land?’

The young brother told him.

‘I want this. Give me that old basket and your knife.’

The older brother set off up through the forest. When he came to that mountain he sat upon a rock and waited.

After a while he felt a rush of air and a beating of wings was heard.

There, as he gazed towards the west, towards the setting sun, a bird appeared from its bright rays, beating its wings, coming closer.

It landed next to him.

‘Why do you sit here all alone?’

‘I am poor. I have nothing.’

‘Is this true or is this false?’

‘It is true, I am poor. I have nothing. I want gold!’

‘Climb on my back,’ said the great bird. ‘I will take you to the Island of the Sun. There you may take one piece of gold.’

Away from the mountain the great bird flew.

Over the forest the great bird flew.

Over the waters the great bird flew.

To the Island of the Sun the great bird flew.

As it landed, the sun set behind the island.

The older brother looked and saw sparkling gold everywhere. He picked up one piece and placed it in the basket.

‘The basket seems empty. I may as well take another.’

A second piece he placed in the basket, then a third.

He continued picking up the largest chunks of gold until the basket was completely full.

Then he turned. As he turned he saw that the bird had flown away and the sun was rising. He could not escape.

The young brother inherited his older brother’s land. He tended the land well and with love.

What he produced he shared with others of the community.

    </string>

    <string name="story9">

Once upon a time, a monkey lived in a tree by a river. The monkey was alone as he had no friends or family but he was happy and content. The tree gave him plenty of sweet jamun fruit to eat. It also gave him shade from the sun and shelter from the rain.

One day, a crocodile was swimming up the river. He climbed on to the bank to rest under the monkey\'s tree.

        \'Hello,\' called the monkey, who was a friendly animal.

\'Hello,\' replied the crocodile, surprised. \'Do you know where I can get some food?\' he asked. \'I haven\'t had anything to eat all day and I am hungry.\'

Now you might think that the crocodile would want to eat the monkey, but this was a very kind and gentle crocodile and the thought never entered his head.

\'I have lots of fruit in my tree. Would you like to try some?\' said the monkey, who was also very kind.

He threw some jamun fruit down to the crocodile. The crocodile was so hungry that he ate up all the jamuns even though crocodiles don\'t usually eat fruit. He loved the sweet tangy fruit and the pink flesh made his tongue turn purple.

\'Come back whenever you want more fruit,\' said the monkey, when the crocodile had eaten all he wanted.

Soon the crocodile was visiting the monkey every day. The two animals became good friends. They would talk, tell each other stories and eat lots of sweet jamuns together.

One day, the crocodile told the monkey about his wife and family.

\'Please take some fruit for your wife as well when you go back today,’ said the monkey.

The crocodile\'s wife loved the jamuns. She had never eaten anything so sweet before but she was not as kind and gentle as her husband.

\'Imagine how sweet the monkey would taste as he eats these jamuns every day,’ she said to her husband.

The kind crocodile tried to explain to his wife that he could not possibly eat the monkey.

\'He is my best friend,\' he said.

The crocodile's greedy wife would not listen. To get her husband to do what she wanted, she pretended to be ill.

'I am dying and only a sweet monkey's heart can cure me!' she cried to her husband. 'If you love me, you will catch your friend the monkey and let me eat his heart.'

The poor crocodile did not know what to do. He did not want to eat his friend but he could not let his wife die.

At last, he decided what he must do and the next time he visited the monkey he asked him to come to meet his wife as she wanted to thank him in person for the lovely jamun fruit.

The monkey was pleased but said he could not possibly go because he did not know how to swim.

'Don't worry about that,' said the crocodile. 'I'll carry you on my back.'

The monkey agreed and jumped onto the crocodile's back.

So the two friends moved out into the deep wide river.

When they were far away from the bank and the jamun tree, the crocodile said, 'I am so sorry but my wife is very ill and says that the only cure is a monkey's heart. I am afraid that I have to kill you, although I will miss our talks.'

The monkey thought quickly and said, 'Dear friend, I am very sorry to hear of your wife's illness. I am glad that I will be able to help her but I have left my heart behind in the jamun tree. Do you think we could go back so that I can fetch it?'

The crocodile believed the monkey. He turned and swam quickly to the jamun tree. The monkey jumped off his back and climbed into the safety of his tree.

‘I thought you were my friend,' he called. 'Don't you know that we carry our hearts within us? I will never trust you again or give you fruit from my tree. Go away and don't come back.'

The crocodile felt foolish. He had lost a friend and a supply of good sweet fruit. The monkey had saved himself because he had thought quickly. From that day on, he never trusted crocodiles again.
    </string>

    <string name="story10">

A long time ago, much longer than most people can remember, elephants could fly! They had four enormous wings and they whizzed through the sky so fast that it amazed the other animals. But these big beasts were sometimes also stupid. But shhh… the other animals would keep quiet about it and never discuss it.

Because the elephants were so strong and so fast, God decided to take their help. He could ride on these big beasts and they could help Him to put the finishing touches to the world. In a moment He could be in China and from there, within the blink of an eye, He could zoom off to Iceland! And these elephants were so strong that they pushed and pushed at mountains and icebergs, shifting them until everything in the world was perfect. For example, they helped God to put the Himalayas in India – and in Tanzania, they had Mount Kilimanjaro. By riding on these elephants, God sorted the whole world out and made it absolutely perfect.

Once this big job had been completed, God told the elephants that they could have a permanent holiday. Uh… that is, until He had something else for them to do. Now the elephants did not have very much to do. Then do you know what happened?

The elephants became idle and to pass their time, they talked about the old days. They talked about how strong they had been. They talked about how fast they were, and how God had favoured them. And the more they talked, the more they came to think that they were much, much better than all the other animals on Earth.

They were definitely the most important!

The elephants chattered idly to each other. ‘Look at that peacock,’ they would say unkindly. ‘See how ugly and brown his little wings are compared to ours!’ And they would always make sure to raise their voices high so that the little peacock could hear their mean words. And the poor peacock, who was kind and humble at heart, could not disagree with the elephants. He thought, ‘The elephants are right. I am small. My wings are not beautiful like those of the fairies and nor am I strong like the elephants.’

As time went on, the elephants began to pride themselves. They began to think that they could do whatever they wanted. The greedy elephants would take all the bananas from the banana tree, leaving none for the other animals. The other animals were sad because they did not get even one banana for their meal. And you know what the elephants did with these bananas in their trunks?

The elephants would come down into a village, any village they liked – and they would spread their wings like a carpet and sit down to have their picnic. The whole village would be squashed under the weight of the elephants. The houses would be flattened and the fields would be ruined and the villagers would be deeply upset.

The poor villagers were very angry at the destruction of their homes, and the animals with their empty stomachs were also very cross. And so God decided enough was enough. These proud and greedy elephants had gotten far too big for their trunks, and needed to be taught a lesson!

God invited all the elephants for a chat. He said to them, ‘Oh mighty elephants, listen to Me. I am very grateful to you for helping me make the world perfect. So I want to throw a party. Only for the elephants.'

All the elephants were very happy. One elephant said to another, ‘See! Even God can see how strong and brave we are – how much we have helped Him. It is right that He should have a party just for us!’

So the greedy elephants, all puffed up with pride and confidence, turned up to the feast one by one. As promised, God had found the best food, and there were mountains of it! Bright yellow bananas, deep red pomegranates, tangy guavas, juicy mangoes… whatever fruits you could imagine, they were there. The greedy elephants were delighted. And they ate it all up. Every last bit.

By the end of the meal the elephants were so full that one by one they dropped off to sleep, surrounded by discarded banana peels and mango skins. This was the moment God had been waiting for. When the last elephant had closed his eyes, God took out a very big knife. Quietly, He went to each elephant and chopped off their wings. And He gave these beautiful wings to the little peacocks. The little peacocks were so happy that they ran into the forest to sing and dance.



Have you seen the peacocks dance, the peacocks dance, the peacocks dance?

Have you seen the peacocks dance, all around the trees?

Yes, I’ve seen the peacocks dance, the peacocks dance, the peacocks dance,

Yes, I’ve seen the peacocks dance, all around the trees.


And now think of the elephants. When the elephants finally awoke from their long sleep, they were shocked to see the beautiful peacock swishing his impressive feathers at them. They were really, really angry. But God had no time to listen to their complaints. Instead He said, ‘I want you elephants to become nicer, kinder. I want you to use your strength and help the villagers to re-build their houses.’

The elephants felt very ashamed of what they had done. They resolved to help the villagers as much as they could. So even today, in every village, there are elephants that come and go, helping people as they pass by.
    </string>
</resources>